

203-300-4188 colinrlly@gmail.com https://www.colin.world

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE:**

Software engineer with 2 years of professional experience seeking full time employment in the Denver area

#### **SKILLS:**

Python, JavaScript, Java, C#, .NET, React, Redux, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, API Development, Unix/Linux, HTML/CSS, Flask, Django, Node.js, Git, Jest, Agile, TDD

## **PERSONAL PROJECTS:**

## log-time.com

May 2018 - Present

- Launched a time tracking web-app
- Interacted with the Google Calendar API to save user's activity records to Google Calendar
- Interacted with users on Reddit and through email
- 2.5K users have logged 7.8K sessions

## **MVP Food Computer**

May 2018 - December 2018

- Contributed to an open source project while working directly with the owners
- Built a controlled environment food growth chamber
- Programmed a Raspberry Pi to record environment data to a web server
- Used React to displayed the captured data on my Website
- Wrote a Medium article which has been viewed 20K times

#### **EDUCATION:**

## **Rochester Institute of Technology**

Rochester, NY

B.S. Computer Science

Coursework completed, degree expected May 2020 contingent on 14 weeks of employment

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

# Web Developer | Shine Wedding Invitations

September 2018 - December 2018

- Created a Node.js command line tool to manage the pipeline between products and price tables
- Used a dependency graph to refactor and remove cyclical dependencies from Shine's legacy modules

# Internal Developer | RIT WITR 89.7 Radio Station

January 2018 - September 2018

- Wrote HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript to develop a new website
- Used Python/Flask to create a resource mindful music logger (logger.witr.rit.edu)

# Production Intern | BMW Manufacturing

August 2017 - December 2017

- Leveraged OracleDB to correlate millions of robot cycle time records to car production numbers
- Used SQL to extract key performance indicators from petabytes of data

# Software Intern| Flight Plan

May 2017 - August 2017

- Implemented Django, SQLite, and Bootstrap to build an employee time tracking website
- Worked with the IT department to launch the website on an Apache server